Robin Lovell (he/him)

Software Engineer

robinlovell13@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub | +1 413 813 1087

SUMMARY

Customer-focused full-stack developer with over a year of experience delivering technical solutions to Fortune 500 companies. Recognized for strong technical proficiency, problem-solving abilities, and track record of project success in previous role at Perficient. Adept in technologies including JavaScript, React, AWS, and PostgreSQL.

SKILLS

Backend: Java, RESTful APIs, JSON, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Python, Express.js, GraphQL, Object-Oriented Programming

Frontend: JavaScript, React, TypeScript, Flutter, Dart, SvelteKit, ES6, HTML, CSS, Syntactically Awesome Stylesheets, D3.js

Cloud and DevOps: Git, AWS (DynamoDB, Lambda, S3, etc.), GitLab, Azure DevOps, Docker, Cloud Native Architectures, CI/CD Pipelines, Jira, Vercel

Other: HTTP, Windows, Linux, JUnit, Bash, Agile Scrum Development Practices, Amazon Connect, Twilio, R, Machine Learning Algorithms, Statistical Analysis, Generative Al

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner Certificate 05/2022
Scrum Alliance - Scrum Foundations Certificate 09/2022

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer and Data Manager

02/2024 - present

Common Crow Natural Market

- Develop and maintain company website to match owners' desired features and style.
- Manage inventory and sales data utilizing Excel and ECRS Catapult, maintaining accuracy and efficiency.
- Author training materials and conduct training sessions on operational protocols.

Associate Technical Consultant (Software Engineering)

1/2022 - 03/2023

Perficient

A top digital consultancy that provides technical solutions to Fortune 500 companies.

Amazon Connect Disaster Recovery Tool - JavaScript | Git | Agile Scrum | Jira | AWS (Serverless Application Model, Lambda, Step Functions, DynamoDB)

- Engineered a scalable, cloud-native disaster recovery solution for Amazon Connect cloud contact centers, generating approximately \$2-5 million in revenue and averting potential client outages.
- Made key technical decisions, rigorously tested and resolved critical bugs, and refactored to decrease runtime and complexity by 10X, leading to project success.
- Conducted daily Scrum meetings with a cross-functional development team and client, accurately scoping work, communicating progress, and adapting to client needs and evolving project demands.

Multi-channel Messaging Application Proof of Concept - Flutter | Dart | AWS | GraphQL | Git | Azure DevOps | MS Teams API | Twilio | WebSockets | Agile Scrum

- Developed proof of concept to demonstrate secure, multi-channel messaging functionality between administrators, financial advisors, and clients.
- Rapidly upskilled in GraphQL and AWS AppSync to develop data models and achieve real-time data sync, replacing WebSockets; debugged the user interface using
 Flutter and Dart, and integrated MS Teams, meeting key project milestones.
- Presented live demos to highlight features and value to stakeholders.

IVR-to-Flowchart Tool – JavaScript

Blog Post

- Created a tool using JavaScript and Mermaid to transform complex contact center workflows into clear, visually distinct flowcharts.
- Enhanced client understanding and interaction with these flows and reduced labor required for generating project documentation.
- Authored an in-depth blog post on the tool, showcasing the company's innovative services and driving client acquisition.

PROJECTS

Kaella Ecommerce Website - SvelteKit | JavaScript | AWS | Azure DevOps | Vercel | Git | Stripe

03/2023 - 10/2023

- Built an ecommerce website to enhance the digital presence and market reach of a Peruvian beauty and fashion small business.
- Collaborated with clients to refine website requirements, leveraging Azure DevOps for program and project management and JavaScript for custom web scraping to
 migrate existing data.

$Health\, Tracker\, -\, SvelteKit\, |\, JavaScript\, |\, AWS\, |\, Vercel\, |\, Git$

10/2023 - 12/2023

• Crafted a flexible and privacy-centric health tracking application, enabling users to gain personalized insights into health trends and lifestyle impacts, fostering informed decisions on well-being without compromising data privacy.

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts Amherst, College of Information and Computer Sciences, B.S. Informatics, GPA: 3.4

05/2021

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

- Volunteer @ Common Crawl
- Open Source Contributor @ Kubernetes
- Self-study: Implementing LLMs, Software Architecture, UX design